Finding Aid for M-Pathways Project (University of Michigan) records, 1996-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Technology Management
  The Technology Administration series (1.5 linear feet) consists largely of the University of Michigan PeopleSoft (UMPS) Technical Discussion Database. The database is available in printed form and is also on CD-ROM (located in Box 1). The database was designed for documents related to the design of the technical architecture, implementation of technology, and technology related policy and procedures. The database served as a means for discussion on specific technical issues. When used for discussion, it appears that the Technical Infrastructure Lead Manager, William Wrobleski, marked the opening of the discussion with a document announcing the discussion point. Other technical team members would then submit responses on the specific technical issue within the area that Wrobleski placemarked in the database for that discussion thread. While some of the discussions resulted only in a few responses, the Citrix WinFrame discussion is a good example of the depth of some of the discussion threads. This discussion also includes a good example of the information sharing utilized in the project across other technical teams in the Big Ten. The technical documents in this database span from 1995 to 2000.
  - University of Michigan PeopleSoft (UMPS) Technical Discussion Database 1996-2000
    - (Archivist's documentation on UMPS Technical Discussion Database, November 10, 2000. Electronic version of UMPS database is located on CD-ROM CD Box 1.) (Box 8)
    - Application and Tools Fixes discussion 1996 (Box 8)
    - Architecture, Authentication and Authorization discussion 1998 (Box 8)
    - Architecture designs, Database Architecture 1999 (Box 8)
    - Architecture design discussion 1997-2000 (Box 8)
    - Back-up Recovery and Disaster Recovery Architecture 1997 (Box 8)
    - Batch Processing discussion 1996-1998 (Box 8)
    - Certification discussion 1996 (Box 8)
    - Citrix WinFrame discussion 1996-1998 (Box 9)
    - Client Architecture August 1997 (Box 9)
    - Contract Consulting 1996 (Box 9)
    - Crystal Reports discussion 1997 (Box 9)
    - Database Instances discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Distributed Computing Environment 1996 (Box 9)
    - Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) 1997 (Box 9)
    - Electronic Forms Architecture 1998 (Box 9)
    - File Server discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - GAMS: UniVerse/TOADS discussion 1997 (Box 9)
    - Internal Job Postings 1996 (Box 9)
    - Macintosh discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Move to Production discussion 1996-1999 (Box 9)
    - Network Issues discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Operational Data Store FIN 1998 (Box 9)
    - PeopleSoft Software Deliveries 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - PeopleSoft Security Administration discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Planning Technical Team Tasks 1995 (Box 9)
    - Policies and Procedures 1997-1999
      - Oracle Security Policy 1998 (Box 9)
      - Proposed M-Pathways Access Process 1997 (Box 9)
      - Security for Non-Production Databases 1997 (Box 9)
    - Printing discussion 1996-1999 (Box 9)
    - Problems
      - Miscellaneous 1997 (Box 9)
      - Process Scheduler 1996-1997 (Box 9)
      - Security 1996-1997 (Box 9)
      - Workstation discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Process Scheduler discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Project Timelines discussion 1996 (Box 9)
    - PSSAFE discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Security discussion 1997-1999 (Box 9)
    - Server Hardware discussion 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Systems Architecture Diagrams 1996-1998 (Box 9)
    - Standards and Procedures for Migration 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Technical Architecture Scope March 1997 (Box 9)
    - Technical Infrastructure Lead Team (TILT) Agenda and Meeting Minutes 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Technical Inquires about PeopleSoft 1995-1997 (Box 9)
    - Technical Milestone Reports 1997-1998 (Box 9)
    - Technical Standards discussion 1997 (Box 9)
    - Technology Management Scope Documents 1997 (Box 9)
    - Technology Standards 1999-2000 (Box 9)
    - Tools Evaluation Committee (TEC) discussion 1996 (Box 9)
    - University of Michigan Computer Environment (UMCE) Meetings 1997 (Box 9)
    - Upgrade discussion 1997 (Box 9)
    - Work Planning discussion 1997 (Box 9)
    - Workstation Research and Deployment Team 1996-1997 (Box 9)
- Videotape
  The Videotape series contains one videotape created on May 20, 1993 featuring several technologists from the University of Michigan. The production is largely a discussion of client/server architecture and views on how the architecture may effect services, such as access to information, within a university community. It includes sections on: Ad hoc Query and Reporting Environment; Data Administration; Andyne GQL Finance Demo; Campus-Wide User Involvement; Data Modeling; Data Availability across Multiple Systems: Finance, Personnel and Student; and User Benefits)
  - Client/Server Innovation: Strategic to Solutions, May 20, 1993 Segment 4: University of Michigan Data Access Project (Box 9)
- Website
  The WEBSITE series (391 digital documents, 46.4 MB) was first captured via Teleport Pro software application in November 2000. The website series is divided into ten subseries: Financial Administration System, Getting Started with the M-Pathways System, Help Desk, Human Resources System, Library Documentation, Physical Resources System, Project Overview, Research Administration System, Student Administration System, and Training. This series includes the entire contents of the M-Pathways Project website as it appeared on the capture date. The 2000 capture includes HTML, Excel, PDF, and PowerPoint files. The M-Pathways project website targets as its primary audience the University of Michigan administrative system user. The Project Overview subseries, however, does contain organizational project information that would be of interest to other Universities and Colleges undergoing similar system projects. As well, the Wolverine Access section in the Student subseries includes registration information and procedures targeted to university students.
  - Financial Administration System circa 1998-2000
    The Financial Administration System subseries contains documentation to support University of Michigan system users for the General Ledger and Procurement modules. A system overview, FAQs, and curriculum information is included for both modules.
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - Financial Reporting (Box 1)
    - Summary of Reports (Box 1)
    - General Ledger (Box 1)
    - Procurement (Box 1)
    - Advisory Group (Box 1)
  - Getting Started with the M-Pathways System
    The Getting Started with M-Pathways System subseries provides information for first time system users. The information contained here includes the " Getting Started with M-Pathways User Guide" (PDF format), system software and hardware requirements, and the system access and compliance form (PDF format).
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - Obtaining Access (M1) (Box 1)
    - User Guide (Box 1)
    - On-line Help (Box 1)
  - Help Desk
    The Help Desk subseries includes "current" questions about the systems and business processes that were asked during end user training sessions, system FAQs arranged by module, and numerous system shortcut guides.
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - List of FAQs (Box 1)
    - Unit Liaison List (Box 1)
  - Human Resources System
    The Human Resources System subseries contains the least amount of information. At the time the website was captured, the Human Resources system was the last system yet to be "rolled-out" to the University. The subseries only contains a brief overview of the project. No information is made available about the project timeline, staff, or system objectives.
    - Human Resources System (Box 1)
  - Library Documentation
    The Library Documentation subseries is comprised largely of citations to M-Pathways and PeopleSoft related articles in university and external publications. The articles date from 1996-2000. The subseries also includes the spring 1998 edition of the project newsletter TransExpress (PDF format).
    - Library Documentation (Box 1)
  - Physical Resources System
    The Physical Resources System subseries includes information about the Asset Management, Inventory, and Space Management modules that began operation in January 1998. The subseries includes an overview of the system, system related FAQs, instructions and forms, and both the Space/Utilities/Plan and the Asset Management Data Dictionary (PDF format).
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - Asset Management
      - Inventory (Box 1)
      - Status Report (Box 1)
    - Space Management
      - Space Reporting (Box 1)
      - Status Report (Box 1)
  - Project Overview
    The Project Overview subseries provides summary information about the project scope, cost, and history. The subseries includes summaries of project accomplishments arranged chronologically dating from August 1997 to October 1999. This subseries also includes an informative section on the technical architecture of the systems design and implementation. An informative pointer in this section is a summary of remarks made at the December 1998 M-Pathways Interchange by Bill Wrobleski, Technical Infrastructure Manager.
    - Project Schedule (Box 1)
    - Project Accomplishments (Box 1)
    - Project FAQs (Box 1)
    - Project Summary (Box 1)
    - Project Scope (Box 1)
    - Project Cost (Box 1)
    - PeopleSoft (Box 1)
    - Roles of the Schools (Box 1)
    - Project Organization (Box 1)
    - Project History (Box 1)
    - Technical Infrastructure (Box 1)
    - Status Report (Box 1)
  - Research Administration System
    The Research Administration System subseries provides extensive information on the four related research system initiatives. The initiatives include the Grants Application and Management System (GAMS), Research Administration Management System (RIMS), the Programmed Research Information System (PRISM), and the efforts towards developing the PeopleSoft GRANTS system. Unlike the other subseries, this subseries also contains an interesting section on the theory of business process re-engineering (BPR) and how BPR relates efforts of the research projects.
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - RIMS
      - Implementation Plan (Box 1)
      - Advisory Group (Box 1)
      - Background (Box 1)
    - GAMS
      - Objectives (Box 1)
      - Training (Box 1)
      - Status Report (Box 1)
    - GRANTS
      - Objectives (Box 1)
      - Status Report (Box 1)
    - BPR
      - Objectives (Box 1)
      - Initiative (Box 1)
  - Student Administration System
    The Student Administration System subseries contains information about the training and labs available for student system users. The subseries includes the Data Dictionary for Student Recruiting and Admission, Student Records (August 2000), Student Financials (October 2000), and Third Week Count (July 2000). The dictionaries are available in PDF versions. The subseries also contains the "SA Updates," an electronic mail communication sent to all student system users. The newsletter updates captured in this website date from August 16, 2000 to November 14, 2000. The subseries also contains valid values (Excel format) and data models (PDF format) for the student data warehouse.
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - Student Admin. Beta Project (Box 1)
    - Student Reporting
      - DW Enhancements (9/99) (Box 1)
      - Valid Values/Glossary (Box 1)
      - Getting Started (Box 1)
      - Campus Community (Box 1)
    - Financial Aid
      - Item Types (Box 1)
      - FAQ (Box 1)
      - Student Financials (Box 1)
      - FAQ (Box 1)
      - Curriculum (Box 1)
      - Academic Advising (Box 1)
      - Wolverine Access
        - FAQ (Box 1)
        - Preview (Box 1)
        - New Terms/Concepts (Box 1)
    - SA Updates (Box 1)
  - Training
    The Training subseries includes the training philosophy statement for the M-Pathways systems and the training curriculum. This subseries also contains information about other communications directed to system users in the section titled Interchanges. The archived website contains pointers to past Interchange sections as well as documents distributed at the June 2000 Recruiting and Admissions Interchange.
    - Section Overview (Box 1)
    - Course Descriptions (Box 1)
    - P-Card Training (Box 1)
    - Labs (Box 1)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series (176.7 MB) documents various components of the M-Pathways project. The website targets as its primary audience the University of Michigan administrative system user, although some sections, such as the "Project Overview" would be of interest to a broader audience. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1997 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2000 and 2006. Content includes announcements, publications (such as newsletters), documentation of procedures, and information on the Human Resources System, Physical Resources System, Research Administration System (2000 version), Student Administration System, data delivery (2006 version), and associated training.
  - 1997-2006
    (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
  - 2000, .ZIP file
  - May 19, 2006, .ZIP file